早上好我是卡伊·吕斯达尔
Good morning, I'm Kai Ryssdal.
今天是2008年9月15日 星期一
It is Monday today, the 15th of September, 2008.
而今天会成为我们脑海中
And this is going to be one of those days
记忆深刻的一天
that lingers in the mind for awhile.
人们会谈论到
It's going to come up in conversations
他们会问“还记得那天吗？”
where people say, "You remember when?"
加利福尼亚印地麦克银行的破产
The closing of California's IndyMac Bank
很可能会成为美国史上
has resulted in what could turn out to be
最为严重的银行破产案
the most costly bank failure in US history.
道琼斯指数已下跌超过800点
The DOWhas dropped more than 800 points,
目前还不清楚危机是否已经过去...
and it's not clear the crisis is over...
昨晚 在华盛顿召开了紧急会议
Last night, there was an emergency meeting in Washington.
国会领导人被告知
The leaders of Congress were told
国家的金融体系面临着崩溃的危险
the Nation's financial system was facing imminent collapse.
花旗集团裁掉了53000名员工
53,000 Citigroup workers are losing their jobs.
早上好
Morning.
嘿
Hey.
嘿 有我的留言吗？
Hey, do I have any messages?
威尔科克斯让你去见她
Wilcox wants to see you.
她在五楼会议室
She's in the fifth floor conference room.
今天早晨在俱乐部打了一次86杆
Shot an 86 at the club this morning.
她说有要紧的事
She said it was important.
谢谢 萨利·威尔科克斯认为所有的事情都很重要
Sally Wilcox thinks everything's important. Thank you.
有没有人能猜出我今天早上在俱乐部打了多少杆？
Anyone want to take a guess at what I shot at the club this morning?
别客气 猜猜看
Go ahead, take a shot.
...没人猜？
Just... no?
前面44杆 后面42杆
Forty - four in the front, 42 on the back.
哦 鲍勃 不会吧 不 我做到了
Oh, no you didn't, Bob. Yes, I really did.
这是事实
It's true.
发生什么了 有人死了吗？
What happened, somebody die?
科纳尔？
Conal?
他们关闭了移动和纽波特纽斯
They closed Mobile and Newport News.
把造船工业和铁路产品合并了
They merged Ship Systems with Rail Products.
- 裁了多少人？ - 科纳尔 你妻子在1号线上
- How many? - Conal, your wife's on one.
与首次经济萎缩...
With the economy contracting for the first time...
- 亲爱的 - 飞船系统那边裁了3000人
- Hi, honey. - 3,000 at the ship yards.
传言说另一块在这儿
Rumor is another couple hundred here.
嗯 我已经得知一些坏消息
Uh, I've got some bad news.
出什么事了？
What's going on?
鲍勃 你认识信托公司的迪克·兰德里吗？
Bobby, you know Dick Landry from Legal?
公司正在整合分歧
The company is consolidating divisions.
需要裁员的部门不得不做出艰难的决定
Difficult decisions had to be made in areas where redundancy surfaced.
我们决定给你一笔可观的遣散费
We have structured a generous severance package for you.
你为我们工作了12年因此有资格获得 额外12周的全额工资
Your 12 years with us entitles you to 12 weeks, full pay.
和红利
And benefits.
- 你要解雇我？ - 鲍勃 你先坐下
- You're firing me? - Come on, Bobby. Sit down.
同时我们还会为你提供再就业服务
We're also offering you outplacement services,
以帮助你找到一份新工作
to help you secure your next employment.
- 吉因知道这件事情吗？ - 你先坐下
- Does Gene know about this? - Please sit.
你知道吗 萨利？
You know what, Sally?
去死吧
Fuck off.
- 吉因在吗？ - 他在芝加哥
- Is Gene in here? - He's in Chicago today.
我们研究了500个正在规划中的计划和方案
We've reviewed our pipeline of some 500 projects and programs,
决定把重点放在那些更有利的市场机会上
focusing on those with significant marketing opportunities,
同时放弃了那些不会短期产生效益的方面
and jettisoning everything that won't contribute immediately
选取了37个有希望发展的计划
to our profitability, selecting 37 as promising strategic growth programs
其余的以后再做考虑
and setting aside the rest for future consideration.
奈德·哈斯克尔 J.P.摩根
Ned Haskell, J.P. Morgan.
麦克拉里先生您先前在关于2011财年的报告中曾说
Mr. McClary, you were talking earlier about fiscal 2011.
你说服我们
You've done a good job of convincing us
随着信贷市场的降温
that with the credit markets frozen,
2010财年的销售收入会放缓
your sales revenue in 2010 will slow.
你说的非常好这里已经没我什么事了
Great, my job here is done.
您能否谈一下关于2011您预期有什么样的增长吗？
Can you talk about 2011 and what sort of a percentage increase you anticipate?
奈德 你的人和我的人都喜欢谈论数据
We all like to talk percentages, Ned, your people do, our people do.
你是想说你不指望你的部门
Are you suggesting that you aren't expecting
明年有任何增长吗？
any growth in your division next year?
我认为我们面临的来自国外的竞争压力在增加
I'm suggesting that we face increased foreign competition,
并且一个不景气的信贷市场对大型资本的支出就像造船工业
and a difficult credit market for large capital expenditures like ship building.
您的意思是说 2011零增长？
So, no growth in 2011?
我深信虽然造船工业会仍然面临挑战
I am confident that while ship building will remain challenged,
但交通系统部门的其它部分
the rest of the transportation systems group
仍将会为GTX在未来的几个季度
will continue to make significant
的增长做出重要贡献
contributions to growth at GTX in the coming quarters.
是的也许是
Yes, in the back.
实话实说是好办法吗？
Honesty is the best policy?
天呐 你就不能说一次谎？
Christ, could you just try to be a little less candid for once?
欺骗金融分析师是我们的新盈利计划吗？
Is lying to financial analysts our new profitability plan?
你想怎么样？更多的夸张误导
What do you want? More inflated guidance so we can under - perform
然后在下一财年的四个季度再次业绩不佳？
in all four quarters again next year?
2011?
2011？
我在担心我们明天的股价？
I'm worried about our share price tomorrow.
塞林杰只会在那里吹
Salinger's gonna blow a fucking gasket.
该死
Ah, shit.
- 嗯 - 他们还说会解雇谁吗？
- Yeah. - They say who else is on the block?
菲尔 谢谢你的问候
Thanks for the sympathy, Phil.
那 保持联系？
Call you later? OK?
好
OK.
他们有提到什么关于我的事情吗？
Did they say anything about me?
什么？
What?
就是会不会解雇我？
About my still having a job?
你知道的我没问
You know, I didn't ask.
我一直在联系您
I've been trying to reach you.
这个该死的东西没电了 帮我充一下电好吗？
This damn thing's dead. Recharge it for me, will ya?
菲尔在你的办公室
Phil's in there.
菲尔 你随意不用拘束
Make yourself right at home, Phil.
我不会回到厂区那边去
I won't go back to the factory floor.
我有一个孩子在上大学 另一个到秋天的时候也要上了
I've got one kid in college and another going in the fall.
你在说些什么？
What the hell are you talking about?
你跟我开玩笑呢吧 他不知道吗？
You're shitting me. He doesn't know?
萨利·威尔科克斯解雇了一些人
Sally Wilcox let some more people go.
一些？她他妈的解雇了所有人
Some? She fired goddamn everybody.
你也被解雇了？
Did she fire you?
没有但是我已经在这里躲了一整天了
No, but I've been hiding in here all day.
她们关闭了移动和纽波特纽斯
They closed Mobile and Newport News.
解雇了造船系统销售组的大部分人
Laid off most of the ship system sales group.
我不会让这帮混蛋在我工作了30年以后 那么轻易把我解雇
I won't let the bastards just kick me out after 30 years.
那样的话 我会拿把AK-47横 扫这个鬼地方
I'll take an AK-47 to this fucking place first.
- 赔偿... - 你们打算什么时候告诉我
- the compensation... - What were you gonna do,
让我在明天的日志里自己看吗？
let me read about it in tomorrow's Journal?
- 我们正在忙 - 你关闭了我的两个船坞？
- We're in the middle of something here. - You closed two of my shipyards?
合并一些部门的事情公司已经讨论好几个月了
Consolidating divisions has been under discussion for months.
是的但是我想告诉你那是一个烂主意
Yeah, and I told you it was a shitty idea.
我们认真的考虑了那个意见...
We took that opinion into consideration...
那是我的部门！
It's my goddamn division!
这是我的公司！
This is my goddamn company!
你们先走吧
Would you excuse us for a moment, please.
你不应该那样让我难堪
You don't embarrass me like that.
让你难堪？
Embarrass you?
我就出差一天你就撤消了一个我的部门
I'm gone one day and you gut one of my divisions.
股票已经跌停 收益持平
Stock has stalled, revenues are flat.
整个经济都处于衰退中 我们也不例外
The entire economy's flat, we're in the middle of a recession.
我只是关闭了其中的两个船坞 我真应该把 三个都关闭了
I only closed two of the shipyards, I should've closed all three of them.
股票相当不景气
Stock is in the fucking toilet.
每个人的股票都不景气
Everybody's stock is in the toilet.
但股东希望看到自己的股票价值最大化
Well, the stockholders would like to see their share value maximized.
那好办 把这幅德加的画卖了 怎么样？
Sell the fucking Degas. Hmm?
但是 我却听到了你在芝加哥发表了一个这样的讲话
Well now, I heard you put on quite a show in Chicago.
你都做了些什么 你告诉一屋子的分析师
What'd you do, you told a room full of analysts
下一年度不会产生任何经济增长
you weren't going to generate any growth next year.
那你就解雇了300个员工？
Three thousand jobs?
吉因 我们已经不再是一些垃圾的小船厂了
Gene, we're not some shitty little shipyard anymore.
我不会一直向一个亏本的生意里投入资金
I'm not gonna keep pouring money into a losing operation.
我们可以改革 重组
We innovate, we retool...
美国的重工业已经完蛋了
American heavy manufacturing is dead.
钢铁业 汽车业 还有你那没有价值的造船业
Steel, autos, your precious shipbuilding.
未来的重点是医疗 基础设施建设和发电行业
The future's in health care infrastructure, and power generation.
我必须参与那些会影响任何我的部门的决定
I have to be involved in any decision that affects one of my divisions.
你是不会同意那些削减计划的
You wouldn't have approved the cuts.
你会背着我再去董事会那里的对吧？
You'd go behind my back to the board again, right?
他们都是好人 吉姆
They were good people, Jim.
但那与我们无关
They're not our responsibility.
我们是为股东工作的
- We work for the stockholders now.
- 你爸爸在家吗？ - 是的
- Your dad's home? - Yeah.
你去车里把剩下的拿过来好吗？
Can you grab the rest of these out of the trunk?
嘿
Hi.
- 你在家里干什么？ - 做晚饭
- What are you doing home? - Makin' dinner.
- 我们要去杰克家 - 今晚吗？
- We're going over to Jack's. - That's tonight?
今天是迪尔德莉的生日
Dierdre's birthday.
- 我想今晚可能会下雨 - 你知道吗
- I think it's gonna rain. - You know what,
你不想去？好啊
you don't want to come, fine.
那你就不要去
Don't come.
谢谢 儿子
Thanks, bud.
德鲁 你去楼上去写作业好吗？
Drew, can you finish that upstairs, please.
顺便换一条新的牛仔裤
Can you put on a clean pair of jeans, please.
我们晚上要去你杰克叔叔家吃晚饭
We're going over to your Uncle Jack's for dinner.
天啊 你可以不喜欢他 但你应该看 在我的面子上假装一下
Christ, you don't have to like him, but you can pretend for my sake.
我的意思是 他也不喜欢你 但是他至少看在我的面子上
I mean, he doesn't like you either, but at least he cares enough about me
没有那么对待你
not to treat you like a piece of shit.
我被解雇了
They fired me.
什么？
What?
他们今天解雇我了
They fired me. Today.
- 萨利·威尔科克斯干的 - 为什么？
- Sally Wilcox. - Why?
因为公司裁员
Something about redundancies.
- 吉因保证过你不会有事的啊 - 吉因保证过很多事
- Gene said you were safe. - Gene said a lot of things.
我今天根本找不到他
He was nowhere to be found today.
鲍勃 你为他们忙的死去活来的...不 不 我不是那个意思
Bobby, you busted your ass for them... No, no, I'm sorry.
去他们的还有那该死的吉因·麦克拉里和他的承诺
Fuck them, and fuck Gene McClary, and all his promises.
有东西烧焦了
Something's burning.
你明白的在我找到新工作之前
Hey, I... I don't want to tell anybody.
我不想让别人知道 好吗？
You know, until I get another job. All right?
你妈妈呢？
Hey, where's your mother?
嗨
Hey.
你妈妈呢？
Where's your mom?
她头痛 在楼上呢
Headache.
嗨
Ah.
对了 爸爸
Oh, Dad.
学校宣布了我们旅行的目的地
They announced where we're going for our senior trip.
是意大利
Italy.
意大利
哇 非常棒
Wow. Boy, that's great.
我可以去 对吧？
I can go, right?
当然 亲爱的
Of course, sweetheart.
菲尔？
Phil?
什么事？
Yeah?
哦天啊
Oh, God.
安·多尔蒂打电话说她们解雇了科纳尔
Ann Doherty called. They fired Conal.
你没事吧？
Are we OK?
当然
Yeah.
- 我应该准备一下 - 为什么？
- I should get ready. - For what?
我们要去塞林杰家吃完饭
We got Salinger's dinner.
- 哦天啊 我完全忘记了 - 如果你觉得不舒服的话
- Oh God, I completely forgot. - You don't have to come,
- 你可以不去 - 给我几分钟
- if you're not feeling up to it. - Just give me a minute.
我去化一下妆
To put my face on.
吉因？
Gene?
你去哪了？司机半小时后来接我们
Where've you been? The car's picking us up in half an hour.
我可不想再迟到了
I really don't want to be late again.
快一点好吗？否则又迟到了
Can we please try not to be late again?
斯蒂芬妮终于找到了那个桌子 在窗边
Stephanie finally found a table for the window.
我喜欢
I like it.
我还是去吧
I'm comin'.
- 最近怎么样？ - 挺好的
- How are you? - Good, good.
嗨
Hey, guy.
那个诉讼案怎么样了 鲍勃？
How go the suit wars, Bobby?
还好杰克
All right, Jack.
这周又有多少高薪的工作
Move any more high- paying American jobs
给了那些亚洲人？
offshore to Asian shitholes this week?
最近集中力都在工会 你懂的
Mostly focused on union busting now, you know how it is.
很意外你能来没有出差或是高尔夫比赛吗？
Surprised you could make it. No early flight, no golf game?
那是都是通常的借口 对吧？
Those are the usual excuses, aren't they?
鲍勃
Oh hi, Bobby.
生日快乐
Hey, birthday girl.
你看起来一点儿也不像35岁了
I can't believe you're 35.
看起来像是刚刚过了21岁的生日
I mean, you don't look a day over 21.
你看到了吧 杰克看看他多会说
Ah, you see, Jack. Now that's how it's done.
鲍勃 你花言巧语 但我喜欢听
You're a liar, Bobby. But I love you for it.
你应该回到你的岗位上去
You need to get back to your post,
- 做你的烧烤 - 好的马上
- barbecue boy.-all right, all right.
鲍勃 自己去弄点儿喝的
Why don't you grab yourself a drink, Bobby.
果汁机里有玛格丽塔酒
We got some margaritas in the blender,
后面冰箱里还有啤酒
we got some beers out back in the cooler.
谢谢
Thanks.
传给我传给我！
I'm open! I'm open!
干的漂亮 干的漂亮
Nice play action. Nice play action.
让他的老朋友来颁布
Who better to introduce this year's Man of the Year Award,
这个年度人物大奖再好不过了
than the man who's known him longer than anyone else.
吉因·麦克拉里 GTX全球运输系统
Gene McClary is Executive Vice President of GTX,
的执行副总裁
Global Transportation Systems.
同时也是GTX的首批员工之一
He's also, I'm told, one of GTX's first employees.
吉因·麦克拉里
- Gene McClary.
谢谢
Thank you.
如果我没有记错的话 事实上 那时我是GTX的唯一雇员
Actually, if memory serves, I was GTX's only employee at the time.
那时候没人想来格罗斯特的造船厂 每年都要亏损几百万
Nobody wanted Gloucester Shipbuilding. Years of multi-million dollar losses.
同时又有着同行业里最高的劳动成本
Highest labor costs in the industry.
虽然有着那么糟糕的开始
But from those humble beginnings,
吉姆还是带领着格罗斯特成长成了今天的GTX
Jim was able to grow Gloucester into GTX,
一个拥有60000名员工 年收入110亿美元的公司
with 60,000 employees and 11 billion dollars in gross annual revenue.
因此 我很荣幸地介绍我的...
So, it is my privilege to introduce my...
...老朋友
...oldest friend.
大学室友 我结婚时的伴郎
College roommate, best man at my wedding
同时还是我见过的最烂的网球选手
and the worst tennis player I ever met.
女士们 先生们 我的老板 吉姆·塞林杰
Ladies and gentlemen, my boss, Jim Salinger.
谢谢 大家
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
毫无疑问 如果没有吉因·麦克拉里的支持和领导才能
Without a doubt, you don't build a company like GTX,
就不会有今天的GTX
without the support and leadership of men like Gene McClary.
我是GTX的罗伯特·沃克
Hi, Robert Walker, GTX.
直走到大厅尽头
Down at the end of the hall.
西装不错
Nice suit.
- 谢谢 - 不知道往哪走？
- Thanks. - Orientation?
- 是的 - 那边
- Yeah. - That way.
谢谢
Oh, thanks.
- 替我做“Tiger” - 什么？
- Do the tiger for me. - What?
- 走到尽头 - 谢谢
- Down the hall. - Thanks.
首先 我来告诉你们再就业服务都干什么
First, let me tell you what outplacement is not.
我们不是职业介绍所
We are not an employment agency.
我们的目的是帮助你们
We are here to help you help yourselves.
现在你们需要做的是把你们的所有朋友列举出来
Now, you all need to put together a networking list of all your friends.
那些你的支持者 竞争者
That's suppliers, competitors,
甚至是那些在普通谈话中坐在你旁边的人
people you sat next to at a convention.
邻居 牙医 总之所有的人
Neighbors, dentists. Anybody and everybody.
你们需要一份新的简历
You need a new resume.
你们可能需要送出去几百份 因此 好好做
You're gonna be sending out hundreds so make it good.
结束
Endings.
我们对它们并不熟悉
We're not used to them.
恐惧 焦虑...
Fear, anxiety...
...失败
...loss.
你们当中的有多少人有这些感觉？
How many of you are feeling these things?
结束
Endings.
恐惧
Fear.
忘掉这些感觉 最后才能成功
Change. And finally, success.
好了 大家都站起来
OK, everybody up.
快点儿 不要因为周围有人坐着就感到不好意思
Come on, no use sitting around feeling sorry for ourselves.
都站起来这个游戏叫做“Tiger”
Up, up. This is called the Tiger.
当我们需要打起精神的时候我们就做这个游戏
We do it when we need to get our energy up.
我会成功！
I will win!
为什么？
Why?
我会告诉你为什么 因为我有信心
I will show you why, because I have faith,
勇气和热情
courage, enthusiasm.
- 每个人都要站起来 - 好的
- Everybody, this time. - I'm all set.
我会成功！
I will win!
为什么？因为我有信心 勇气和热情 非常好
Why? Because I have faith, courage, enthusiasm. Good.
我会成功！
I will win!
鲍勃·沃克有打过电话吗？
Did Bobby Walker call back?
- 有过 昨晚打过 - 留言了吗？
- Yeah, last night. - Leave a message?
没有
Not one I'd care to repeat.
问问他中午一起吃饭怎么样
See if he can come by for lunch today.
股票涨了6点 还不错
Stocks up six, not bad.
我的养老金账户里的钱都买了GTX
My 401K is all GTX.
如果持续下去 我80岁之前就可以退休了
This continues, I may get to retire before I'm 80.
因为造船工业和铁路产品的合并
With ship systems and rail products merging,
我们重新分配了销售区域
we are reassigning sales regions.
我们和皇家加勒比油轮公司的生意谈的如何了？
How are we doing with Royal Caribbean?
他们很不安
They're nervous.
看到我们每15分钟就会在彭博资讯上出现一次很不高兴
Don't like seeing us on Bloomberg every 15 minutes.
嗯 稳住他们 我们需要那笔订单
Well, calm them down. We need that boat.
我们用一半的员工怎么才能应对
How are we supposed to cover the same number of accounts,
同样数量的订单？
with half the staff?
我一个月中已经有两个星期没有回家了 我该怎么跟我的孩子们解释？
I'm already gone two weeks out of four. What am I supposed to tell my kids?
告诉他们你已经很幸运了 没有失业
Tell them you're lucky you still have a job.
有许多死账户
Inactive accounts.
我想知道我们要怎么做才能把失去的生意 从一个一个的
I want to know what we're going to do to get the business back.
客户手中拿回来
Client by client.
- 这里有人了 - 好吧
- It's taken.-all right.
嗨
Hey.
- 过来坐这里吧 - 谢谢
- Come in here. - Thanks.
非常感谢
Appreciate it.
- 橄榄枝 - 你对于他们来说是敌人
- Friendly bunch. - You are the enemy.
你是他们找工作上
Another warm body they got to claw their way over
有威胁的竞争者
to get back to the corporate feed trough.
- 你就不会成为威胁？ - 我这个人非常安全
- Yet you're not threatened. - I'm a very secure individual.
而且你看起来并不像一个工程师
Besides you do not look like an engineer.
- 工商管理硕士？ - 是的
- MBA? - Yeah.
如果你认为你的周围都是敌人
If you knew your way around a guided missile system,
那我就不得不拿一个冰锥在你的脑袋上 敲一敲
I'd have to shove an ice pick in the base of your skull.
- 我会记住你说的话的 - 你的前雇主真是下血本啊
- I'll keep that in mind. - Your previous employer
施乐的传真机还有咖啡
has spared no expense. Fax machine, Xerox, coffee.
以后打算怎么办？
How was orientation?
我感觉像是有人剃光了我的头
I felt like someone was going to shave my head
并且在上面敲
and make me beat a drum.
那么 呃...你要怎么做
What, uh... What do you got to do
才能到那边的办公室里去工作
to get yourself in one of those offices?
你的公司要为他们的每一个人支付额外的钱
Your company has to pay extra for one of those.
多数都是执行副总以上的人
Exec VPs and above mostly.
角落那个办公室里的是伊斯曼柯达的首席财务官
Corner one has a Eastman - kodak CFO in it.
他们给你开出了什么条件
How long they give you?
三个月的全额工资和四个月的离职咨询
Three months full salary, four months outplacement.
- 你呢？ - 呃 9个月的全额工资和离职咨询
- How about you? - Um, nine months of both.
我已经来这4个月了
Been here four.
我认为不过多久我就会找到新工作
I don't think it'll take me more than a few days.
没有冒犯你的意思
No offense.
没关系
None taken.
对不起 我来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
- 最近怎么样了？ - 还不错
- How you holding up? - Good.
- 玛吉怎么样？ - 她也很好我们都很好
- Maggie all right? - Yeah. She's great, we're fine.
一杯格兰利威
Glenlivet, rocks.
鲍勃 那件事情和我无关
It wasn't my call, Bobby.
有人买公司股票之前 塞林杰面临着提高股票价格的巨大的压力
Salinger's under a lot of pressure to boost the stock price
因此 他决定重组公司
before somebody buys in and makes him break up the company.
如果不裁员的话会有更多的人失去工作
We'll lose a lot more jobs in a merger than we have in this downsizing.
你是想让我认同公司的做法吗？
You trying to appeal to my sense of the greater corporate good?
我帮你联系了一些人
I've been calling in some markers.
洛克希德-马丁公司的汤姆·博登 雷神公司的派特·莱希
Tom Borden over at Lockheed, Pat Leahy at Raytheon,
你会有机会认识他们
you'll recognize most of them.
打起精神来我们吃点东西吧
Come on, let's get something to eat.
我没有胃口
I lost my appetite.
鲍勃 拿着那个
Take the names, Bobby.
不用你操心我的工作问题
Don't bother reassigning my accounts.
当我找到一份能和你竞争的工作以后 我会把失去的都夺回来
I'm gonna steal them back when I get a job with your competition.
- 嗨！ - 嗨
- Hey! - Hey.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- 今天怎么样？ - 还行
- How'd it go? - Great.
- 是吗？ - 是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
- 好吧 - 中午和吉因一起吃的饭
- All right. - Lunch with Gene,
他帮我联系了一些人
he gave me some names.
他人还不错
That's big of him.
我的意思是 他其实没必要帮我你明白吗？
I mean, he didn't have to do anything, you know?
- 是的 - 这些是什么？
- Yeah. - What is all this?
我们的抵押贷款下个月就要到期了
Ah, our mortgage is resetting next month.
除了还要付牙医的钱
With that and paying off the orthodontist,
还有去年夏天去迪斯尼乐园的账单
and last summer's Disney World trip,
我们的积蓄不多了
we don't have much of a cushion left.
我不需要积蓄
I don't need a cushion.
你的保时捷的账单 信用卡还有爱国者队的门票？
Your Porsche payments, the credit cards, Patriots tickets?
我已经告诉过你了 我把今年爱国者的门票给达瑞尔了
I told you I'm splitting the Pats tickets with Darryl this year.
好除了那些每个月光是在外出吃饭
OK, well, just eating out and doing the damn dry cleaning
和干洗上就要花掉600块钱
is costing us 600 bucks a month.
我想也许我可以回去工作
I was thinking maybe I could go back to work.
别
Uh-uh.
不是全职的只是那种每周上几天班的
Not full - time, just a few shifts a week.
不用
No.
3M公司需要一个新的销售经理
3M needs a new General Sales Manager.
我会给布莱恩·科林斯打个电话 约他下周一起吃个饭
I can call up Brian Collins, and have breakfast with him next week.
好吧 但我们现在需要削减开支
OK, well we're gonna need to cut back.
取消圣诞节外出滑雪的计划
Cancel skiing at Christmas,
停止缴纳一段时间的俱乐部会费
stop paying the club dues for awhile.
如果情况真的变得糟糕了 我可以去干苦力活
If things get really bad, I can bag groceries.
- 我还可以站在街角... - 别说那么混蛋的话 好吗？只不过...
- I can be on the corner... - Don't be a jerk, OK? Just...
不许出去大手笔的花钱 就在家吃吧
No more big purchases. Just eat at home more.
你好？
Hello?
凯文 什么事？
Hey, Kevin. Yeah?
好的我把电话给他 他就在我跟前
Yeah, let me get him for you. He's right here.
干什么？
What?
他在报纸上看到了关于裁员的新闻
He read about the layoffs in the paper.
- 那又怎么样？ - 你不告诉他？
- So what? - You gonna tell him?
是的我不告诉他 我现在可不想谈论
No, I'm not gonna tell him, because I don't need a lecture
什么有关于父母责任的话题
on parental responsibility right now.
嗨 爸爸 怎么了？哦 那件事啊？
Hey, Dad, what's going on? Oh, that?
- 那些都是虚构的
- That's all manufactured.
他们想让我当总裁 我不得不谢绝他们
They're trying to offer me a CEO job. I had to turn them down.
我是来送礼物的
I come bearing gifts.
珍藏40年的格兰菲迪切
Glenfiddich, 40 year old.
- 单一纯麦的 - 非常不错
- Single malt. - Nice.
当然
Yeah, it better be.
斯特里克那个王八蛋送来的
Strick sent it over. That bastard.
- 那是阿拉斯加吧 - 是的
- That's Alaska. - Yeah.
天啊 吉因 那些都是美好的时光
Goddamn it, Gene. Those were good times.
是最好的
The best.
嗯 你和辛西娅今年新年的时候
Well, you and Cynthia thinking about joining us
还会和我们一起去太阳谷吗？
at Sun Valley for New Years again this year?
我也不知道能不能去 利亚姆之前说要在圣诞节
I don't know if we can, Liam's been talking about
的时候带着苏珊和孩子来我家
coming home for Christmas with Susan and the kids.
该死 爷爷 把他们一起带来
Ah, hell, bring them along, Grandpa.
有那么多孩子缠在她身边
Kay'd probably think she'd died and gone to heaven
凯可能以为她已经死了
with a bunch of kids running around.
你不能在众多高级职员面前挑战我的威信
Can't have you challenging me in front of senior staff.
他们尊重你 你这样质疑我的判断
They respect ya. Question my judgment,
会有损我在他们面前的威信
you undermine my authority.
我想知道 你会你全力支持我吗？
I need to know, can I count on your full support?
很好
Good.
你还好吧？
You OK?
我今天中午和鲍勃·沃克一起吃了个饭
I had lunch with Bobby Walker today.
我以为他会直接把酒泼到我的脸上
I thought he was gonna throw a drink in my face.
吉因 你是他的老板 不是他的父亲
You were his boss, Gene. Not his father.
苏和我想这个月的晚些时候
Sue and I are thinking of sneaking down to Palm Beach
偷偷的去棕榈滩度个假
for a weekend. Later on this month.
你知道的就是购购物 打一打高尔夫
You know, some shopping, some golf.
你可以派一架公司的包机给我们吧？
Think you could get us one of the corporate jets?
好吧 我们坐商务航班去
Fine. We'll fly commercial.
今天股市收盘的时候上涨了两点
Stock closed up two today.
我的股票比我早上起来的时候
My options are worth a half a million dollars more
多了50万美金
than when I woke up this morning.
伍德沃德先生需要我留下来吗？
Need me to stay, Mr. Woodward?
不用了 谢谢你 南
Ah, no thanks Nan.
明天见
We'll see you tomorrow.
千万不要想着在学校就把所有
Don't even think about eating all the candy
的糖果都吃掉 最多只能吃三块
you get at school. Three pieces, that's it.
你知道吗 你看上去真够恶心
- You look disgusting, you know that?
我给布里奇特打了个电话 约好了时间
So, I called Bridget, and made an appointment.
- 谁？ - 就是那个房地产经纪人
- Who? - The realtor.
我想至少应该先预约一下
I think we should at least list it.
看看能不能得到优惠
See if we get any offers.
我不会同意卖房子的
We're not gonna sell the house.
我们是不需要什么优惠 但是现在市场环境这么不景气
We don't need to accept an offer, but with the market so bad,
可能需要一段时间才能卖掉 你明白吗？
it may take us awhile to sell it, you know?
如果我们陷入困境
If we get stuck.
我们不会陷入困境的
We're not gonna get stuck.
- 我看起来怎么样？ - 找到工作的可能性很大
- How do I look? - Highly employable.
好的
OK.
那布里奇特呢？
Bridget?
得了吧 我们不会卖房子的
C'mon. We're not gonna sell the house.
- 一路顺风 - 好
- Have a good day. - OK.
财政部长波尔森今天早上宣布
Treasury Secretary Paulson this morning
布什政府打算向
announced that the Bush Administration is about to
银行业注资数十亿美元
inject billions of dollars into the banks
作为救援金融的一项措施
as a part of the financial rescue strategy...
好了 先这样吧
- All right, great.
下周记得给我打电话 我会告诉你结果的
Give me a call next week, I should have an answer for you.
- 好了 谁是下一个？ - 沃克先生
- All right, who's next? - Mr. Walker.
你是沃克先生？我是乔伊斯·罗宾逊 很抱歉让你等了这么久
Mr. Walker? Joyce Robinson, sorry to keep you waiting.
介意我吃点儿东西吗？
Mind if I have something to eat here,
因为一会我还要去开会
I have another meeting right after you.
请便
Go right ahead.
从你的简历上看 你在GTX工作了12年
So, it looks like you worked at GTX for 12 years.
是的其中有三年是部门销售经理
I did. Divisional sales leader for three of those years.
很惊讶他们居然解雇你了
Oh. Surprised they let you go.
- 你我都一样 - 你有处理过区域销售吗？
- You and me both. - Have you handled regional sales?
我就是在区域销售起家的曾经在加利福尼亚的马丁-马利埃塔公司工作
I came up in regional sales. I worked for Martin-Marietta in California.
嗯 很好我们打算扩大南部的业务
Mm - hmm. Well, we're looking to expand in the south.
我们需要派人去小石城工作
We need someone in Little Rock.
阿肯色州？
In Arkansas?
搬迁问题？
Is relocation a problem?
不 不 呃...我本打算继续待在这里的
Uh, no, no. Um... I had hoped to stay here,
因为我从小就在这里...
because I'm from the area...
你没有填写申请表上的薪资要求
You left the salary space blank on your application.
呃 这个你明白的 我们需要当面讨论
Well, uh, you know. That's a negotiation.
我以前在GTX工作加上奖金后的年薪是 120万
I was making 120 at GTX plus incentives.
但是我知道现在情况不一样了
But I know times are different now.
年薪110万我也很愿意接受 最好还有奖金
And I'd be willing to accept 110, and hope for bonuses.
是这样 我们地区销售经理
Well, our base salary is 65,000 a year
的基本工资是每年65000
for regional sales directors.
我...我可以成为市场营销副总裁的一个招牌
I, I responded to an ad for the Vice President of Marketing.
可是这里有很多非常合适的应聘者
Well, we've had a number of highly qualified applicants for that position.
我才是最合适的人
I'm a highly qualified applicant for that position.
我才是最合适这个职位要求的人
不好意思 非常抱歉
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
一定是因为刚刚在你的等候室里等了2个小时
I must've had too many cups of coffee while I was
喝了太多的咖啡
sitting in your fucking waiting room for two hours.
非常感谢你接待我乔伊斯 如果让我给你点建议的话
Thanks for your time, Joyce. Just between the two of us?
建议你少喝点可乐
You can probably skip the Diet Cokes.
它们对你没什么好处
They're not helping you.
吉姆非常担心 认为他会是下一个目标
Jim's worried, thinks we're a target.
谁能在经济衰退中赚到那么多钱呢？
Who can get together that kind of money in the middle of a recession, huh?
这正是他擅长的
It's what he does.
那想说明什么？想要挑拨我们？
Then what? He splits us up?
出售医疗设备 铁路产品同时关闭了格罗斯特内
Sell off the healthcare unit, rail products, close Glosterne.
他仍然还有消费类电子产品 涡轮机
He'll still have consumer electronics
和国防部的生意
and the turbine and defense departments. Whammo.
我们只是棋子 妈的 再过一个季度
We're a bargain. Hell, one more quarter
利普顿就能获得足够的票数去争夺管理权
and Lipton will be able to put together enough votes
并组建他自己的该死董事会
to wage a proxy battle and install his own damn board.
吉姆绝对不会不战而降
Jim's not gonna give up without a fight though.
我相信他肯定早已派人
I'm sure he's already got somebody out there
去找救星了 可能是基茨也可能是罗伯茨？
looking for a white knight. Keats, maybe Roberts?
肯定是有足够多钱的人
Somebody with deep pockets.
- 怎么了？ - 没什么
- What? - Nothing.
多跟我说说关于制造业资本贬值的事儿...
Tell me more about capital depreciations of manufacturing...
该死
Shit.
办公室打来的 我3点半要见一些高级职员
It's my office. I have the senior staff at 3:30.
- 换个时间吧 - 不行
- Reschedule. - I can't.
下周二一起吃午饭怎么样？
How about lunch again next Tuesday?
恐怕不行
I don't think so.
也许可以
Maybe.
拜拜
Bye.
你好我找乔纳斯·高尔
Hi, Jonas Gall, please.
我是罗伯特·沃克 不 您不认识我
Robert Walker. Nope. Doesn't know me.
尤尼可公司的麦克·塔尔伯特推荐我来的
Mike Talbet recommended me from Unicor.
呃 他说盖勒先生可能需要一个高级销售人员
Uh, he said that Mr. Geller may have an opening for a senior sales associate.
好吧 那太遗憾了
OK. That's too bad.
没关系 我已经不是第一次被拒绝了
It's OK. Not the first time I've heard it.
好吧 再见
All right, bye.
北大西洋石油钻井平台上的工人每小时收入65美元
Sixty - five dollars an hour for oil rig workers
如果你有深海商业认证的话
in the North Atlantic. Another thousand a week
每周还可以多赚1000美元
if you got your commercial deep sea certification.
我们不也是吗？
Doesn't everybody?
我去年在耶鲁拿到了我的学位
I got mine last year at the Y.
梅花6可以放在红桃7上
Six of clubs on the seven of hearts.
我找萨利·威尔科克斯 谢谢
Sally Wilcox, please.
施工 危险废弃物清除还有飞机机械师
Construction, hazardous waste removal, aircraft mechanic.
感谢上帝让我有一个博士学位 对吧？
Thank God I got my doctorate, huh?
她在吗？我是鲍勃·沃克
Hey, is she in? It's Bob Walker calling.
他又给她打电话了
He's calling her again.
嗨 萨利 我是鲍勃·沃克
Hi, Sally. Bob Walker.
非常感谢你没有回我的电话
Uh, thanks for not returning any of my phone calls.
如果你回电话了 我可能会问 为什么你不通知就把我解雇了
If you do return my call, I would love to know why you fired me
你个婊子
without any notice, you fucking cowardly bitch.
嘿 我终于明白她为什么一直不回电话了
Gee, I wonder why she never calls you back.
轻松多了
Feels good though. God.
你知道我是怎么想的吗？
You know what I think?
- 该下班了 - 下班时间？
- It's quitting time. - Quitting time?
才三点半
It's 3:30.
一个人被拒绝的承受能力是有限的
A man can only take so much rejection.
我去喝点东西 有人想来吗？
I'm thirsty, who's coming?
- 科纳尔？ - 当然要去
- Conal? - Sure, why not?
我也去
I'm in.
好吧 我也去
All right, why not?
如果你们两个去了
I know if you two are going,
肯定会非常有意思
it's gonna be good.
有多少股份？
- For how much?
证监会文件上说是百分之三点八
SEC filing says 3.8 percent.
- 先生们 戴上头盔 - 他只想尽可能提高我们的股票价值
- Hard hats, gentlemen. - He's just trying to boost our stock.
他把自己的股份提升到了百分之十
He gets it up ten a share, he walks away with
然后就带着几百万的利润走了
a couple hundred million in profit.
利普顿想要的不仅仅是几百万这么简单
Lipton wants more than a couple hundred million.
他想得到整个公司
He wants the company.
我们的股票价格还是太低了
Well, our share price is still too low.
这使我们成为很具有诱惑力的目标
It's making us a very tempting target.
保罗 那边的就是你未来的办公室
Paul, your office is over there.
- 所有人都在这层楼吗？ - 不
- Whole floor Legal? - No.
这层楼只有我们五个人
This is just for the five of us.
首席财务官的办公室 大卫 诺亚 你们的办公室在那边
CFO's office, David, Noah. You are over here.
会议室 私人餐厅
Conference rooms, private dining room.
还有卫生间和浴室
Bathrooms and showers.
还有健身房和厨房
Gym and kitchen.
过来吉因
Gene, come here.
这里是你的
This is you.
不用太兴奋 我的办公室要更大一点儿
Well, don't get too excited. My office is gonna be much bigger.
你们感觉如何？
What do you think?
- 漂亮极了 - 太神奇了
- It's beautiful. - This is amazing.
石灰华 还有落地窗户
Travertine. Floor to ceiling glass.
如果沿着那个方向 就能直接看到波士顿全貌
If you look that way you can see all the way to Boston.
嘿 帮我拿下
Hey. Help me.
- 帮你？你需要帮助吗？ - 是的
- Help you? You need help? - Yeah.
- 你今天怎么样？ - 你闻起来满身的啤酒味
- How you doing? - You smell like a brewery.
- 怎么会呢？ - 我不知道
- How did that happen? - I don't know.
德鲁在那干什么？
What's Drew doing?
- 在等你 - 等我？为什么？
- Waiting for you. - Me? Why?
他很担心你
He's worried about you.
- 好了 伙计 等一下 - 好的
- OK, dude, but wait up. - OK.
怎么了 小伙子？
What's going on out here, bud?
我不是小孩子了 我能处理事情
I'm not a baby. I can handle stuff.
我失业了
I lost my job.
你以为是什么事儿？
What did you think it was?
我以为你和妈妈吵架了
You and mom, maybe.
我和你妈妈很好
Me and mom are all right.
你会找到新工作的对吧？
You'll get another one, right?
当然
Yeah.
你没有必要为我担心 明白吗？
Hey. You don't have to worry about me. OK?
看着我
Hey, look at me.
你真的没必要为我担心 明白吗？我是你爸爸
You don't have to worry about me. All right? I'm your dad.
你能理解我吗？
You understand me?
我会没事的
I'm gonna be fine, OK?
今天亿万富翁投资者亚瑟·利普顿
Billionaire investor Arthur Lipton today
加强了他的竞争力来应对GTX的变动
stepped up his campaign for changes at G TX,
他给每位股东发了一封信
issuing a letter to shareholders accusing
指责高管的管理不善
executives of mismanagement...
这些意味着什么？
What does it all mean?
反正不是好事
Nothing good.
有什么事吗 菲尔？
Need something, Phil?
我们失去了皇家加勒比油轮公司的那单生意
We lost Royal Caribbean.
我们还有红莓果酱吗？
Do we have any cranberry jelly?
卡森 做到你表弟的旁边...
Carson, round up your cousins...
弗兰 我来帮你端
Let me help you with that, Fran.
谢谢
Thank you.
孩子们 去洗洗你们的手 擦擦脚
Boys, wash your hands, wipe your feet.
真不错
Beautiful.
杰克 生意怎么样？
How's business, Jack?
生意挺好我们在罗克斯伯里得到了一个装修大单
Business. Well, we got a big renovation in Roxbury,
就在我们去年做的那家的旁边
next to the house I did last year.
等到九月份完成的时候一定能赚不少钱
Nice bonus, when I finish by September.
- 如果你九月份能完成 - 九月份肯定能完成
- If you finish by September. - By September.
当你快要完成的时候记得告诉我
Whenever you're ready to plumb the place, give me a call.
我有一个很不错的科勒卫浴
I got a special on Kohler.
好的
Good.
- 工作怎么样了 鲍勃？ - 还行 杰克
- How's work, Bobby? - Good, Jack.
招募更多的每天一美元的老挝童工
Line up more dollar a day Laotian preschoolers to
在曼谷给你缝网球鞋
stitch tennis shoes for you in Bangkok?
杰克 我是干制造业的
I'm in manufacturing, Jack.
那些每天一美元的老挝童工
The dollar-a - day Laotian preschoolers aren't tall enough
根本就够不到柴油发动机上的螺丝 所以 不行
to turn the screws on the diesel engines, so no.
我前几天在报纸上看到了一些关于你们老板塞林杰的报道
You know I was reading about your guy Salinger in the Globe the other day.
你现在还读报纸呢 很好
Do you read now? Good.
读的不多
Very small words.
上面说 他去年比GTX普通员工多努力700倍
Said he, uh... he made 700 times what the average GTX worker made last year.
你怎么认为的？塞林杰比邮轮船体里的电焊工 铆钉工
What do you think? Salinger working 700 times harder
更加努力700倍？
than the welder pounding hot rivets into a tanker hull all day?
我们为什么不让孩子们开始祷告？
Why don't we say grace so the kids can start?
好了 卡森？你来帮我们做祷告怎么样？
OK, Carson? Would you do the honors?
亲爱的上帝 感谢您赐予我们食物
Dear God. Thank you for the food
谢谢您让我们能够在感恩节这天团聚
and for letting us be together on Thanksgiving.
谢谢您让每个人都有一个健康的身体
And for everybody being OK.
希望您能帮助我爸爸找到工作
And please help my Dad find a job.
那样的话他就不会总不开心了 阿门
So he won't be unhappy all the time. Amen.
好吧
OK.
- 想喝点酒吗？ - 弗兰这桌菜真丰盛
- Want some wine? - It's a nice table, Fran.
谢谢
Thank you.
你明白的如果事情变得糟糕了 我可以 呃...
You know if things get tough, I could, uh...
今年冬天我可以随时提供帮助
I could always use some extra help this winter.
搬石膏板？
Hanging drywall?
是的可能是个很累的活？
Yeah, it'd be lots of work.
这次干活的地方 有4000平方英尺
4000 square feet, we're gutting the place.
谢谢 杰克 我不会...
Thanks, Jack. I don't...
...根本就不会干这些活
...exactly see myself pounding nails though.
你知道的非常感谢
You know? Appreciate it.
你丈夫是一个十足的混蛋
Your husband is such a dick.
高盛在为利普顿做尽职调查
Goldman Sachs is doing due diligence for Lipton.
世达律师事务所正在为某人四处打探
Skadden Arps is snooping around for somebody,
可能是安奈特公司 也可能是西蒙诺夫环球集团在波罗的海的公司
maybe Allied, maybe Simonov's Baltic Global, out of Moscow.
巴特尔给出的最高价是多少？
What's the top price Bater'll pay?
利普顿把市场价值调到了100
Well, Lipton put the market value at 100.
好那我们就把股票价值调到102
All right, so we need to get the stock to 102.
那比原有的股价高出了17
That's 17 more a share.
是的诺亚 我可以增持
Yeah, I can add, Noah.
我们已经处在了错失公司季度利润的危险之中
We're already in danger of missing our quarterly.
我们不能像之前那样继续盲目下去了 否则...
We start fooling around and miss our numbers again, we're...
不 我们不需要把股价抬高到100
No, we don't need to get the stock to 100,
我们只需要把它抬到九十几 然后它机会 显现出积极的趋势
we get it in the mid-90's, it'll show a positive trend.
我们该怎么再次提高股价呢？
How are we supposed to boost the share price again?
提高效率 降低成本
Increased efficiencies, lowering costs.
再次裁员
More downsizing.
再次使用之前的那招使股票停盘...
Suppose we try that stunt again and the stock stalls...
日益增长的市场价值不是一个噱头
Increasing market value isn't a stunt.
我们至少应该考虑一下其它选择
We should at least consider alternatives.
把医疗集团出售怎么样？
How about selling the healthcare group?
什么？
What?
- 也许利普顿是对的 - 得了吧 吉因
- Maybe Lipton's right. - Gene, come on.
医疗是现在唯一表现出增长的部门
Healthcare's the only division that's exhibiting any growth.
我不会拆分掉公司
I'm not breaking up the company.
那好吧
All right.
那把新总部大楼卖掉怎么样？
How about selling the new headquarters building?
我们需要那里
We're going to need that space.
如果我们继续裁员的话 我们就不需要了
Not if we keep firing people, we're not.
我不会卖掉新总部大楼！
I'm not selling the new building!
告诉人事部门 让他们再做出一份
Get a hold of Human Resources, have them start making up a list
裁员名单
for another round of downsizing.
等一下吉姆
Wait a minute, Jim.
让我们两个单独谈一会好吗？
Could you guys give us a minute?
你想让我怎么做 同意你说的每一件事？
What do you want me to do, parrot back everything you say?
我常和你说 在我看来什么是对什么是错 而你这么做...是错的
I've always told you what I thought, right or wrong. And this... is wrong.
我还有一个会要参加
I'm late for a meeting.
我们下个月将没有办法偿还抵押贷款
We're not gonna be able to make the mortgage next month.
我和布里奇特谈过了
I talked to Bridget.
她说如果我们再降一点价格的话
She thinks if we price the house low enough
可以以85万的价格卖掉
we might be able to get as much as 850,000 for it.
那比我们买的时候花的钱还少
That's less than we got in it.
是的但是我们花多少钱买的已经不重要了
Yeah, it doesn't matter how much we got in it.
你的补助三个星期后就到期了
Your severance ends in three weeks.
我们的房子会被没收
We're gonna end up in foreclosure.
我们没有足够的钱再买一栋房子
We won't have enough money to put down on another house.
我们只用我的那点儿工资
We're not gonna be able to qualify
是不可能再买一栋房子的
for another house on just my salary anyway.
是 那我们去哪呢？
Well, OK. Where are we gonna end up?
在公园里支一顶帐篷吗？
Gonna pitch a tent in the park?
- 是的 - 好的
- Yeah. - OK.
我们可以搬去和你爸妈一起住
We could move in with your folks.
- 不行 - 他们有两间空置卧室
- No. - They have two extra bedrooms.
玛吉 我们不能去和我父母一起住
Maggie, we're not living with my parents.
只是暂时的
It'd just be temporary.
我宁愿去死
I'd choose death. I opt for death.
是的还不如让我去死
No, I'd have to kill myself first.
前几天杰克说给你提供了一份工作
Jack said he offered you a job the other day
被你直接拒绝了
and you shot him down pretty hard.
你能想象吗？我为你哥哥工作
Can you imagine that? Me working for your brother.
他只是想帮一下忙
He was just trying to help.
怎么帮 让我去搬石膏板？
How, by letting me hang drywall?
你会变得强壮
You'd get back into great shape.
会晒黑 还会长点老茧
Calluses. A tan.
- 在大冬天的 - 是啊 扛那些重物
- In the middle of winter. - Yeah, big broad shoulders
还会让你的肩膀变宽
from carrying all that heavy lumber.
宝贝儿 我明天还要早起
I gotta get up early, babe.
好吗？
OK?
鲍勃·沃克一直在给我留言
Bobby Walker keeps leaving me messages.
我的助手认为他得精神病了
My assistant thinks he's psychotic.
她想申请一个限制令
She wants to get a restraining order.
我相信你更糟糕
I'm sure you've gotten worse.
好吧 你怎么打算的？
So, what do you think?
你圣诞节会外出一两天滑雪吗？
You gonna get away for a day or two for skiing at Christmas?
我也不知道呢 再说吧
I don't know, we'll have to see.
汉森让你再做一份裁员名单是吧？
Hansen get you started on that new list yet?
- 萨利 那天我也在开会 - 昨天
- I was at the meeting, Sally. - Yesterday.
裁多少？多少？
How many? How many?
5000人
5,000.
那这次裁员的标准是什么？
Well, what is the criteria for getting canned this time?
加里·亨特太胖了 也许该让他走
Gary Hunt's put on a few pounds, maybe we should let him go.
还有我听说吉尔·卡特得了癌症
And I hear Jill Carter has cancer.
我们可以节省一大堆的医药费 对吧？
We could save a bundle on her insurance premiums. Hmm?
萨利
Sally.
亿万富翁男孩俱乐部
Ho! Billionaire Boy's Club.
- 计划如何了？
- How's the plotting going?
沃伦·巴菲特还是福布斯上的首富吗？
Warren Buffet still safe on top of the Fortune 500 list?
鲍勃 最近工作找的怎么样了？
How's the job search going, Bobby?
实际上 还不错 他们还在那儿
Good actually, real good. They're out there.
康纳斯先生你的小组先发球
Mr. Connors, your group's on the first tee.
- 埃里克 准备输球吧 - 我们去打球
- Ready to get your ass kicked, Eric? - Let's golf.
沃克先生
Mr. Walker.
我能和你谈一会儿吗？
May I speak to you for a moment?
嘿
Hey.
出什么事了？
What the hell's going on?
我刚刚在俱乐部被撵出来了
I just got thrown off the course at the club.
好了 你先小点声
All right, keep your voice down.
十月份以后我们就没有缴纳过会费
We haven't paid the dues since October?
是的现在许多东西都要花钱
Yeah, I've paid a lot of things.
我看起来像是个他妈赖账的！
I look like a fucking deadbeat!
鲍勃这就是现实 我们现在就是这样的情况
This is real, Bobby, OK? This is happening to us.
你四处游手好闲 不工作 却还要去打高尔夫？
You are wandering around like you're in some sort of a daze,
你的保时捷的问题解决了吗？
but you're playing golf? Getting your Porsche detailed?
玛吉 我需要去寻找机会 你明白吗？
Maggie, I need to look successful. OK?
我不能再像个傻子一样拿着简历到处去找工作
I can't just look like another asshole with a resume.
你应该像那些混蛋一样去找工作！
You are just another asshole with a resume!
我已经开了张补缴的支票
I cut them a check for the balance.
- 放弃吧 - 不
- Cancel it. - No.
我们付不起的
We can't afford it.
不
No.
我应该早就把俱乐部的事情告诉你的
I should have been honest with you about the club,
但是你也没有对我以诚相待啊
but you haven't been honest with me.
我们不再需要这些东西了 对吧？
We're not gonna need these, are we?
也许我们还可以搞一个小型义卖
Maybe we could have a little rummage sale.
你需要找一份工作
You need to get a job.
任何工作都行
Any job.
鲍勃 只有我一个人工作可不行
I can't do this alone, Bobby.
我知道我在那里打高尔夫
I know. I'm out there playing golf.
再过两周 我就没法养活我的家人了
In two weeks, I won't be able to support my family.
情况会好起来的
Things are gonna get great again.
- 不会的 - 我们可以渡过难关的
- No. - We can get through this.
情况再也不会好起来了 对不对？
Things aren't gonna be great again. OK?
我正在努力找工作
I'm trying to get a job.
我已经连续三个月每天都去那儿了
I've been out there every day,
努力地找工作
for three months, trying to get a job.
一份录取信都没有收到
I haven't had one offer.
- 我知道 - 我已经去找了我们认识的每一个人
- I know. - I've been to everybody we know.
甚至是许多我们不认识的人
And a lot of people I don't.
而且我恳求过 我甚至他妈的恳求
And I have begged, I've fucking begged.
为了一个工作机会 或者其它什么的
For a lead, anything.
现在有成千上万的工商管理硕士
There's thousands of new MBAs out there.
没有抵押 没有小孩 每周工作90个小时
No mortgage, no kids. Work 90 hour work weeks, for nothing.
你想让我说实话吗 玛吉？
You want honesty, Maggie?
我是一个37岁的失业的失败者
I'm a 37 year old unemployed loser,
甚至养活不了我的家人
who can't support his family.
好了 听着 你会找到工作的
OK, look. You are gonna find a job.
为那些以你为傲的人工作
Working for people who know how lucky they are to have you.
什么时候都变得这么糟糕了？
When did it all go to shit?
没有变得很糟 你还有德鲁和卡森
It hasn't turned to shit. You have Drew and Carson.
还有你的父母 还有我
Your parents, and me.
你还有我啊
OK, you have me.
至少还需要裁75个人
We're still at least 75 short.
海事部门高级会计主管 黛布拉·海耶斯行不行？
What about Debra Hayes, Senior Director of Accounting, Maritime Sales.
黛布拉·海耶斯已经在公司工作了10年
Debra Hayes has 10 years with the company,
有着很突出的表现
and outstanding evaluations.
他也有一个有着丰富法律经验的丈夫
She also has a husband with a successful law practice.
而且家里还有两个孩子
And two kids who would be delighted to have mommy at home.
她已经60了 她的孩子根本不会还在家住
She's 60, I doubt her kids are still living at home,
更不会天天在那儿喊妈妈
much less calling her mommy.
把菲尔·伍德沃德从表中剔除出去
Phil Woodward's back on this list.
- 他符合标准 - 迪克 我不是在和你说话
- He fits the criteria. - Wasn't talking to you, Dick.
他的薪酬过高并且只是...
He's grossly overpaid and just blew...
- 你怎么回事 聋了吗？闭上你的臭嘴！ - 吉因这个表还只是初步的
- What are you, deaf? Shut the fuck up! - The list is still preliminary, Gene.
我看了一下但是我看到的都是年过50的人
I'm looking and all I see are people over 50
这会使我们受到诉讼的
with enough young ones thrown in to protect us against litigation.
我可以保证这些裁员都是合法的
I'm confident all of these dismissals will stand up to outside legal scrutiny.
那道德上呢？
What about ethical scrutiny?
吉因 我们并没有违法
We're not breaking any laws, Gene.
保罗 我一直以为我们的行事
I guess I always assumed we were
标准都要比那个高
trying for a higher standard than that, Paul.
沃克先生
Mr. Walker.
我是弗雷德·塞耶
Fred Thayer.
请坐吧
Have a seat.
- 谢谢您能接见我 - 当然
- Thanks for seeing me. - Sure.
GTX公司的牺牲品
A GTX casualty.
- 是的 - 你现在怎么样？
- Yeah. - How you holding up?
还好谢谢
Good, thanks.
丹·麦斯极力向我推荐你
Well, Dan Mass gave you a great recommendation.
工商管理硕士 州立大学毕业
MBA, you went to school at State College.
- 大学阶段 是的 - 我妻子是宾夕法尼亚大学毕业的
- Undergrad. Yeah. - My wife went to Penn.
- 真的吗？ - 我非常喜欢那儿
- Really? - Loved it.
加上提成和奖金
Are you, uh, willing to work for 90 a year,
- 年薪90万你能接受吗？ - 当然
- plus commission and bonus? - Uh, yeah.
好消息是我们公司发展的很快 对于你来说有足够的发展空间
Good news is we're growing fast, and there's plenty of head room around here.
但是 我不能给你任何承诺
So, I can't promise you anything.
但是 由于有丹的推荐 还有你的简历
But with Dan's recommendation,
似乎看起来你很适合这个工作
and your resume, you seem like the right fit for the job.
谢谢
Thanks.
谁赢了？
Ho! Who's winning?
谁知道 怎么样了？
Who knows. How'd it go?
- 面试？ - 很好非常好
- The interview? - It's good. It's good.
一起来吧 我们都在玩
Come on, we're all getting our asses kicked here.
你可以替我
Yeah, you can take my place.
蓝色32号 开球！
Blue 32, hut!
我是罗伯特·沃克找特洛伊·塞耶
Robert Walker calling for Troy Thayer, please.
没问题
No problem.
我是鲍勃·沃克找特洛伊·塞耶
Bob Walker for Troy Thayer.
没关系
Um, that's OK.
我只是打电话问一下工作的事
I'm actually just calling in regards to a position.
当然 东北地区销售经理
Uh, sure. Northeast Regional Sales Manager.
已经有人了 哦
It has. Oh.
非常感谢
- Thank you very much.
那是什么？
What's that?
我最后的工资
My last paycheck.
这个家伙唠叨的没完没了
This guy comes babbling on and on and on.
你在宴会放了九种肉汤？
You were at a banquet with nine meat soup?
是的我之前不知道中国菜里有九种肉
Yeah, I didn't know they had nine meats in China.
- 我也不知道 你能列举一下吗？ - 好啊 有牛肉...
- I didn't either, can you name them? - Well there was beef,
- 猪肉 鸡肉 鱼翅... - 吉因？
- pork, chicken, shark fin... - Gene?
- 菲尔 自己找点东西喝 - 吉因
- Hey Phil, grab a drink. - Gene.
放松 菲尔 自己找点东西喝这是个聚会
Relax Phil, grab a drink. Man, it's a party.
萨利·威尔科克斯刚刚把我解雇了
Sally Wilcox just fired me.
去找萨利·威尔科克斯 让她马上过来见我
Find Sally Wilcox, tell her to get her ass up here right now.
她现在就在您的办公室里
She's already in your office.
你居然解雇了菲尔·伍德沃德
You fired Phil Woodward.
- 把他聘请回来 - 吉因...
- Hire him back. - Gene...
天啊 萨利 我们需要谈谈这件事
Goddamn it, Sally, we talked about this.
吉因
Gene.
你也被解雇了？
You too?
去他妈的
Ah, fuck 'em.
他们以为这很难
They think this is tough.
我曾经在格罗斯特的船体车间里工作过 你还记得吗 吉因？
I worked hull assembly at Gloucester, remember, Gene?
我曾经亲自焊接过36英寸的螺旋桨
Try spot welding inside a 36 inch propeller shaft,
每周工作60个小时
60 hours a week.
吉因？
Gene?
吉因！
Gene!
鲍勃 鲍勃
Bobby. Bobby.
你们肯定猜不到谁在乔安娜的办公室
You will never guess who's in Joanna's office.
吉因·麦克拉里最喜欢的马屁精 菲尔·伍德沃德
Gene McClary's favorite ass - kisser. Phil Woodward.
菲尔 你的简历让人印象非常深刻
Your resume's very impressive, Phil.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thanks.
你是从基层的工厂车间开始干起的这点 很少有人做到
You started on the factory floor, not many people can claim that anymore.
你想避开你以前的老同事 任何90年代以前的
You want to get rid of all the ancient stuff, anything pre - 90's.
暂且不说你在GTX的每个职位上工作了 多少年
Instead of listing the number of years you held each position at GTX,
光是列举你担任过的职位和承担过的责任 就已经足够了
indicate your title and responsibilities.
这里还写着你曾经服过兵役
And here, where you've noted your military service,
不用说越南战争
don't say Vietnam.
光是这些步兵的战斗经验已经非常让人印象深刻了
Combat infantryman is impressive enough.
你吸烟吗 菲尔？
You smoke, Phil?
- 偶尔 - 戒掉吧
- Occasionally. - Quit.
雇主们可不希望因为员工的
Employers don't want employee health problems
健康问题搭上大笔的保险费用 菲尔
ratcheting up their insurance premiums, Phil.
你可能还需要考虑一下你的头发的问题
You may want to think about dying your hair,
最好能把那些白头发掩盖掉
get rid of some of that grey.
- 我们互相认识吗？ - 什么？
- Do we know each other? - Excuse me?
你一直在直接用我的名字称呼我
You keep using my first name.
菲尔 我不是你的敌人
I'm not the enemy, Phil.
你看起来已经有60了看起来很糟糕
You're pushing 60, and you look like hell.
你在这里会度过一段艰难时期
You're going to have a rough time out there.
请你告诉我 我的办公室在哪 好吗？
Could you show me to my office, please?
你这里还有窗户
You got a window.
公司要为那个额外付钱的
Company had to pay extra for that.
这些混蛋应该做的事
The least the pricks could do.
你这个东海岸最好的销售人员最近怎么样了？
So how's the best damn salesman on the East Coast?
依然没有工作
Unemployed.
是啊看样子这里很多人都是
Yeah, a lot of that going around.
这里的着装要求很宽松吗？
Dress code pretty lax around here?
你还没有看到休闲的星期五呢
You should see casual Fridays.
你好嗯 嗯
Hello? Yeah. Mm - hmm.
我上周和你公司的另外一个人谈过了
I talked to somebody else from your company last week,
他们说我这个月
and they said I wasn't going to have to
可以不用再次付款
make another payment on that this month.
呃 听着 我不知道你想让我怎么做
Uh-huh. Look, I don't know what you want me to do.
我可以骗你 告诉你我现在正在写支票
I can lie to ya. Tell you I'm writing a check
并且已经给你汇过去了 你马上就可以收到
and I'm putting it in the mail, and you'll have it right away.
明白吗？好吧 我现在就给你写一张支票
OK? I'm gonna write you a check right now,
马上就给你汇过去 你明天早上就可以收到了
I'm gonna put it in the mail and you'll have it tomorrow.
这样听起来怎么样？棒极了
How's that sound? Terrific, outstanding,
很期待吧
look forward to it.
- 用哪一个？运通？ - 按揭
- Which one? American Express? - Mortgage.
伊韦特问我明天晚上能不能去工作
Yvette asked me if I could work tomorrow night.
- 那可是新年夜啊 - 算双倍时间
- That's New Years Eve. - Double time.
- 爸爸？ - 什么事？
- Dad? - Yeah?
你能开车送我去凯尔家吗？
Could you drive me over to Kyle's?
不行 我现在很忙 好吗？拜托
No, I'm busy now. OK? C'mon.
拜托 德鲁
C'mon, Drew.
嘿 你为什么不玩吉他英雄？
Hey. Why don't you play Guitar Hero?
光环怎么样？你该多玩玩XBox
Halo? You should play some Xbox.
嘿 鲍勃 等一下
Oh hey, Bobby. Hang on a sec.
德鲁！过来
Come here. Hey! Drew!
德鲁！
Hey! Drew!
妈的在外面就事事不顺心
Damn it. There's a fucking nor'easter outside.
在家还有孩子和我生气 就因为
Kid's pissed off because I won't drive him to Cotuit
就因为我没有在他想去科士伊拜访 Matlocks的时候开车带他去
to visit the Matlocks. Right, right when he wants him to.
他已经没有XBox了
He doesn't have the Xbox anymore.
- 为什么？怎么了？ - 他把他还回去了
- Why? What happened to it? - He gave it back.
什么？
What?
他知道我们现在支付不起
He knew we couldn't afford it.
他问我可不可以还回去 我说可以
He asked me if he could, and I said yes.
他是对的我们现在支付不起
He's right. We can't afford it.
杰克 我需要一份工作
I need a job, Jack.
我觉得你还用不上那些东西
I don't think you're gonna be needing that just yet.
很帅的工具腰带
Nice tool belt, man.
鲍勃 继续搬
Keep 'em coming, Bob.
鲍勃
Hey, Bobby.
- 嗯 - 下次一次搬两块
- Yeah. - Grab two this time.
- 该吃午饭了 - 哦
- Lunch. - Oh.
我们去哪？
Where are we going?
你的手套太新了 所以你会起水泡
They're new. That's why you're getting blisters.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 给你 - 非常感谢
- Here.-appreciate it.
嘿 要下来吃晚饭吗？
Hey. You wanna come down for dinner?
我现在想让你直接拿把枪打死我
I want you to take a gun and shoot me.
只需要打死我
- Just shoot me.
来让我看看
Oh, let me see.
啊 我去拿一些抗生素软膏
Ah. Yeah, let me get the Neosporin.
我讨厌你哥哥
I hate your brother.
我他妈非常讨厌他
- I fucking hate him.
我想我不能继续干了
I don't think I can go back.
你可以的
Sure you can.
太稀了 再加一袋混合到里面
Too thin. Add another sack to the mix.
鲍勃工作很简单吧？
Easy work, huh, Bobby?
就像把搬迁费报表
Pretty much like moving cost reports
从箱子里拿到箱子外 我说的对吧？
from the in - box to the out - box, am I right?
没理我
Didn't say nothin'.
...计划使小企业的信贷更加容易
... plans to make credit easier for small businesses.
在现在信贷紧缩情况下他想怎么做到呢？
How does he propose to do that with credit as tight as it is?
总统想拿出150亿美元作为该银行的救助基金
The president wants to take 15 billion dollars for the bank rescue fund.
小企业的贷款基本上都有利于食品和药物 管理局
Basically bankroll small business loans made for the FDA.
他想免收借款人的费用...
He wants to temporarily waive the fee for borrowers...
你今天打算干什么？
What do you have planned today?
还没想好
Not much.
埃德和黛娜邀请我们今晚去吃晚饭
Ed and Dana invited us to dinner tonight.
- 谁？ - 我的老朋友
- Who? - My old friends.
晚上7:30
7:30.
你去的时候记得拿一瓶上好的葡萄酒 好吗？
Pick up a nice bottle of Pinot when you go out, OK?
好的
OK.
奥巴马总统计划斥资2500亿
President Obama plans to spend up to
用来...
250 billion dollars taking...
- 你好我是菲尔·伍德沃德 - 登记一下然后去那边等着
- Hi, Phil Woodward. - Just sign in and take a seat.
见鬼 杰克 你听说了吗？
Hell, Jack, you hear that?
他们解雇鲍勃的时候得到了12周的工资
Bob gets 12 weeks pay when they fucking shitcanned him.
我叔叔汤米为电话公司工作了19年
My uncle Tommy worked for the phone company 19 years.
他们还少给了他10个月的终身医疗
They laid him off 10 months short of lifetime medical.
大概四个月前 他们又把他聘用回去了
They hire him back, like four months later.
以前工资的一半 没有分红
Half his old wages, no benefits.
- 这是什么？ - 你的工资
- What's this? - It's your paycheck.
杰克
Hey, Jack.
这里多出200元
There's an extra 200 in this.
一定是他们搞错了 鲍勃
Must've made a mistake, Bob.
你和你妹妹在一个屋里睡一段时间没问题吧？
You gonna be all right, sleeping in the same room as your sister for awhile?
当然
Sure.
- 都睡了？ - 是的爸爸
- All tucked in? - Yeah, Dad.
我迫不及待的想从这里搬出去
I couldn't wait to get out of this house.
我父母 邻居 还有教徒
My parents, neighborhood, church.
我曾经是个总裁
I was gonna be a CEO.
爸爸 她看起来不错 和孩子很合得来
She seems nice, Dad. Good with kids.
- 她自己有吗？ - 嘿
- She have any of her own? - Hey.
什么？现在也不晚啊
What? Never too late to start.
以为你和苏珊会在6月的时候出去一周
Think you and Susan could get away for a week in June?
我们在斯通沃尔海边租了一个房子
We rented a house out on Stonewall Beach.
6月？也许
June? Maybe.
你现在还很忙吗？
So you keeping busy?
是的我受邀加入几个董事会
Yeah, I've been asked to join a couple of boards.
丹尼克斯 普罗卡
Dynex, Procar.
- 你会去吗？ - 我也不知道
- You gonna do it? - I don't know.
我想我...我想我已经厌倦了董事会的会议室
I think I'm... I think I'm tired of board rooms.
你为什么不自己开一家咨询公司呢？
Why don't you start a consulting firm?
- 行吗？ - 当然
- Yeah? - Sure.
总有一些人愿意付钱雇佣一些有经验的
There's always somebody out there willing to
老家伙来给他们出主意
pay an opinionated old bastard for some shitty advice.
那么你认为6月份去温亚德怎么样？
So, what do you say to the Vineyard in June?
你母亲应该很愿意
Your mother will be OK.
你们两个还联系？
You two talking?
她现在正处于一个非常艰难的时期
She's having a pretty rough time.
她想要卖掉房子
She's talking about selling the house.
快看 爸爸！我又找到了一个鸡蛋
Look Daddy, I found another egg!
麦克呢？
Where's Mike?
- 他 呃 又被逮捕了 - 为什么？
- He, uh, got busted again. - For what?
喝醉行为不检
Drunk and disorderly.
斗殴
Assault.
还打了一个警察
Managed to take a swing at one of the cops, too.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 鲍勃 - 什么事？
- Hey, Bobby. - Yeah?
- 你的那个工具腰带带来了吗？ - 带来了
- Still have your tool belt? - Yeah.
那就拿过来吧
Why don't you grab it.
好的
All right.
- 哦天啊 - 我以为我干的对
- Oh, Jesus. - I thought I had it measured right.
你最好在杰克看见之前把这些都拆了
You got to rip all this shit out before Jack sees it.
- 所有的？ - 是的所有
- The whole thing? - Yeah, all of it.
用你之前速度的两倍重新做
Use your speed square as a spacer.
只需要钉两个点 把那个给我
Get it on two points. Give me that.
好好看着 一个在这 砰
All right? One right there. Bang.
另一个在这儿
Bang.
- 明白了吗？ - 明白了
- You got it? - Yeah.
- 真的明白了吗？ - 是的
- 干完了吗？ - 这面干完了
- Finally done? - This side, yeah.
天啊 简直太烂了
Jesus Christ. That's ugly.
如果 呃 你还需要人的话
If you, uh, need another guy,
我认识一个可以干这个活的
I know somebody who could use a job.
是吗？好吧 不管是谁 我只是希望 他 呃...
Yeah? Well, whoever it is, let's hope he, uh...
...只是希望他不要和你一样慢
...let's hope he isn't as slow as you are.
没问题
OK.
他有没有唱到调上？
He ever sing on - key?
没有
No.
你在干什么？
What're you doin'?
呃 只是喝点酒
Oh, getting drunk.
我给再就业那边打电话 问你有没有时间 一起吃个午饭
I called outplacement, see if you wanted to have lunch.
他们说你好久都没去了
They said you hadn't been coming in much lately.
- 哦 是的 - 已经有几周了吧
- Oh, yeah. - Couple of weeks now.
没开玩笑
No kidding.
小姐
Miss.
我送你回家怎么样？
What do you say, I give you a ride home?
现在不能回家
Can't go home.
罗娜不想让邻居们知道我被解雇了
Lorna doesn't want the neighbors to know
因此我6点之前都不能回去
I got fired so I can't show up until after six.
还让我天天拿着公文包出去
Makes me haul my briefcase back and forth, too.
你看今天早上的杂志了吗？
You see the Journal this morning?
他们列出了去年总裁们的薪资排行榜
They listed how much CEOs made last year.
你知道榜单上的第十七位是谁吗？
You know who was 17th on the list?
GTX公司的詹姆斯·塞林杰
James Salinger, GTX.
一起去看个电影怎么样？
Wanna go to the movies?
我们去看白天场 我肯定现在还有白天场
Take you to the matinee, sure they still have matinees.
我们可以拿着一桶爆米花 和几大杯可乐
We can get a bucket of popcorn, couple of those big Cokes.
- 爸爸 - 小美女
- Hey, Daddy. - Hey, beautiful.
- 你笑什么呢？ - 今天一个男的从芝加哥打电话过来
- What are you smiling at?-a man called today from Chicago.
好像是叫弗雷德·蒙德？
Fred Munder?
他说对你的简历印象非常深刻 希望你给他回个电话
He said he was impressed with your resume, wanted you to give him a call.
他的电话号码就在那边
His phone number's over there.
他就是干这个活的他是个猎头
That's where he's based. The guy's a headhunter.
我之前以为是在波士顿工作
I just thought the job was in Boston.
就是在波士顿 我要去那里
It is in Boston. I'm gonna go there,
我会去住6美元的汽车旅馆 好吧 吃的也会尽量节俭
I'm gonna stay in Motel 6. OK, I'm gonna eat very inexpensively.
知道吗？这个工作是需要一个在交通运输
The job is a vice president of sales and marketing
方面有丰富经验的副总裁
with extensive experience in transportation. OK?
就是这个了这才是我应该干的工作
This is it. This is me. This is my job.
我不知道我还能找到什么其它的了
I don't know what else I can look for.
- 就是这个了 - 好的好的
- This is the one. - OK. OK.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
我跟弗雷德里克·蒙德先生有一个预约 我是罗伯特·沃克
I have an appointment with Frederick Munder. Robert Walker.
沃克先生？
Mr. Walker?
什么事？
Yes?
我是简·尼菲尔德 蒙德先生的秘书
I'm Jane Nefeld, Mr. Munder's assistant.
- 你好 - 你说你有预约
- Hi. - You say you have an appointment.
是的10点钟
Yes. At 10.
我并没有查到
I don't see it.
呃 我之前和蒙德先生通过电话的
Uh, I spoke to Mr. Munder myself.
周五10点
So, Friday at 10.
我们两天前约好的
We talked two days ago.
哦天啊 他是让你下周五来
Oh my, he has you down for next Friday.
也就是17号 你能下周再来吗？
The 17th. Can you come back next week?
我是从波士顿来的
I flew in from Boston.
哦 非常抱歉
Oh, I am so sorry.
我不介意再在这里等一会
I don't mind just sitting in the waiting room.
或者我可以下午再来
Or I could come back this afternoon.
我是今天晚上的飞机
My flight doesn't leave until tonight.
哦 蒙德先生去达拉斯出差了
Oh, Mr. Munder's in Dallas on business.
他下周三才会回来
He won't be back till next Wednesday.
不好意思来晚了 接了个电话
Hey. Sorry I'm late. Got caught on a call.
没关系 我要了一杯喝的
No problem. I got a drink.
看起来不错 我要一杯和他一样的
Looks good. I'll have what he's having.
等一会 你知道我还要什么吗？
Hang on. You know what you want?
我要一份科步鸡肉 不加熏肉
I'll have the Cobb, no bacon.
嗯 肋眼牛排 五分熟 还有薯条
Um. Rib eye, medium rare. With fries.
不好意思时间很仓促
Sorry to rush things.
我1:30的时候还有一个员工会议
I have to get back for a staff meeting at 1:30.
你看起来不错啊 减肥了？
You look great, you losing weight?
嗯 是 我的头发都白了
Uh, yeah, well. Dying my hair.
- 你最近怎么样？ - 我很好 嗯...
- So, how you doin'? - I'm fine. Um...
到处投简历
Sending out a lot of resumes.
你很幸运离开了这里
Ah, you're lucky to be out of it.
呃 据说
Uh-huh. Word on the street is,
你希望找一个驻外的总裁
you're looking for a foreign exec.
你有什么人要推荐吗？
You have someone to recommend?
是的我
Yeah, me.
需要去国外工作
It's international travel.
我有海外工作的经验
I have extensive overseas experience.
我知道你有
I'm sure you do.
菲尔 你介意我问一下...你今年多大年龄了？
You mind my asking... how old are you, Phil?
你就不担心我会起诉你们？
You're not worried I'll sue?
我不会雇一个超过30岁的人 那相当于自杀
I wouldn't hire anyone over 30 for that job. It's a killer.
每6周当中要有5周在国外
Out of the country five out of every six weeks.
- 出国出差不是问题 - 你为什么不花点钱出去旅行？
- Well, travel's not a problem. - Why don't you cash it in?
换做我的话 我就会去海边度假
Shit, I would, go lie on a beach.
我他妈的没有钱去海边度假
I can't afford to go lie on a fucking beach.
菲尔 我不能雇佣你干这个工作
I can't recommend you for the job, Phil,
他们会笑话我的
they'd laugh me out of the office.
罗娜非常担心你以为你开车撞到了树上
Lorna's pretty worried about you. Has you wrapped around a tree someplace.
狗娘养的！
Sons of bitches!
混蛋！
Motherfuckers!
汤姆·布雷迪在他状态最好的时候也不能 把球从这里扔到那栋楼那儿
Tom Brady couldn't hit that building from here on his best day.
萨拉该给布朗的学费还没给
Ah, Sarah's tuition for Brown is due.
我写了一张支票 但却没有抵押贷款
I write the check, I can't make the mortgage.
- 菲尔 我可以... - 不 别说了
- Phil. I could... - No, you stop it.
不用
No.
你知道最糟糕的是什么吗？
You know the worst part?
世界还是和以前一样
The world didn't stop.
每天早晨还是会有报纸送来
The newspaper still came every morning.
每天早上6点洒水喷头自动关闭还有...
The automatic sprinklers shut off at six and...
隔壁的杰夫 还是每周六清洗他的汽车
Jeff, next door, still washed his car every Sunday.
但是我的生活结束了
My life ended.
但是 你知道的根本没有人在乎
And, you know, nobody noticed.
- 鲍勃 - 嗯
- Hey, Bobby. - Yeah.
- 老板说可以下班了 - 知道了
- Boss says it's quitting time.-all right.
- 杰克呢？ - 还在工作
- Where's Jack? - Still working.
- 让一下我把这个搬出去 - 他在干什么？
- Come on, I'm buyin'. - What's he doing?
他工作的很晚争取在最后期限前完成
He's working late to make the completion deadline.
- 拿到利润 - 他不用我们帮忙吗？
- Get the bonus. - He doesn't want our help?
- 他不能雇我们 - 雇我们他就赚不到钱了
- He can't pay us. - Pay us out of the bonus.
他需要保证收支平衡
He needs the bonus to break even.
他低价竞标这个项目为了让我们整个冬天都有工作
He underbid the job to keep us working through the winter.
能让玛吉送萨利回家吗？
Could Maggie give Sally a ride home?
我们曾经在这里干过活儿
We used to make something here.
当我们在文职工作中迷失的时候回来看看
Back before we got lost in the paperwork.
那时这里有个军舰 就在这儿 后面那儿
At one time, we had a frigate, right here, back there.
导弹巡洋舰
Guided missile cruiser.
菲尔就是从这里开始的从船体装配
Phil started out here, in hull assembly.
他那时是个骨瘦如柴的小混蛋
He was a skinny little bastard.
毫无畏惧 他可以在单人座板上倒挂
Fearless. He'd hang upside down all day long
一整天在离车间地面70英尺的地方
in a bosun's chair, 70 feet off the shop floor
焊接一条里面的缝 我的意思是天啊
welding an inside seam. I mean, Jesus.
一班2000人 每天三班倒
Two thousand men a shift, three shifts a day.
6000个人在那个车间里赚血汗钱
Six thousand men earned an honest wage in that room.
为的是养家糊口
Fed their kids, bought homes.
为的是赚钱供他们的孩子上大学
Made enough to send their kids to college.
为的是买一辆二手车
Buy a second car.
建造一些他们自己能够看得到的东西
Building something they could see.
并不是资产负债表上的数字 而是一艘真正的船
Not just figures on a balance sheet, but a ship.
他们能看得见摸得着的
They could see, smell, touch.
他们知道他们的价值 知道那是干什么的
Those men knew their worth, knew who they were.
第一天你赚50美元
One day you're making fifty dollars
第二天你赚了5000 直到有一天你赚了500万
the next day, 5,000. And then one day, five million.
疯狂的计划就开始了
Start out with a crazy plan.
开始冒巨大的风险
Take insane risks.
几乎没有足够的钱来养活家人
Barely make enough money to feed your family.
不是下地狱就是上天堂
Not a chance in hell you're going to succeed.
突然 你获得了所有这一切
And then, all of a sudden, you've got all these things.
你却开始害怕失去这一切
You get terrified of losing them.
股票期权公司的喷气式飞机
Stock options, corporate jets,
还有在巴哈马的度假别墅
vacation homes in the Bahamas.
不过要知道 事实是...
You know. Truth is...
我喜欢500美元的午餐和5000美元的酒店套房
I like 500 dollar lunches and 5000 dollar hotel suites.
现在我花了30年为自己奋斗到了
Now everything I spent 30 years
这一切 然而其他人却...
trying to build for myself and everybody else is...
已经不在了
...gone.
对不起 玛吉
I'm sorry, Maggie.
为什么？
For what?
因为所有的事 因为我让你失望了
For everything. For letting you down.
你从来没有让我失望过
You haven't let me down.
不 我让你失望了
Yeah, I did.
你以前从来不在我身边
You were never here before.
但是现在你在我身边
And now you are.
我觉得吹风机的通风口好像堵住了 我去看看
I think the dryer vent's clogged. I'll take a look at it.
- 鲍勃？ - 什么事？
- Hey, Bobby? - Yeah?
我可以等
It can wait.
- 这个会议... - 嗨 吉姆
- This meeting... - Hello, Jim.
吉因 最近怎么样啊？
Gene. How ya been?
不太好我最近被我最好的朋友解雇了
Not good. I was recently fired by my best friend.
葬礼上怎么没有看见你
Missed ya at the funeral.
菲尔的事我很遗憾
I was sorry to hear about Phil.
罗娜怎么样？
How's Lorna holding up?
吉姆 我们在这里一起创建了公司
We built something here, Jim. Together.
是一起 不是你自己 也不是我自己
Together. It wasn't just you, it wasn't just me.
是我们一起
It was all of us.
他们每周都会得到工资
They got a paycheck every week.
他们有病了 受伤了都会有医疗保险
Medical if they got sick. Disability if they got hurt.
天啊 这是公司 不是慈善协会
Hell, it's a business, not a charity.
你去年赚了2200万美元
You took home 22 million dollars last year
然而这些人却失去了家 失去了婚姻
and these people have lost their homes, their marriages,
甚至是失去了他们孩子的尊重
the respect of their children.
为了生存下来我们做了市场要求我们做的
We did what the market required of us to survive!
昨天晚上董事会接受了安奈特公司的报价
The Board accepted Allied's bid last night.
总共390亿 每股97
Thirty - nine billion, 97 a share.
- 我很遗憾 - 没必要
- I'm sorry. - Don't be.
我的股份价值6亿
My shares are worth 600 million.
- 那祝贺你 - 吉因 你的股份价值多少呢？
- Congratulations. - What are yours worth, Gene?
我要去工作了
I have to get to work.
传球 传球
Give me the ball. Give me the ball.
清楚自己的位置吗？孩子！你输定了
Clear for possession, all right? You're in trouble now, kid!
哦 不！
Oh, no!
击打上面平的地方 就是这样
Hit the head flat on it. There you go.
就是这样 再敲几下把它敲下去
That's it. Try a little more action. Sink it.
- 鲍勃？ - 什么事？
- Hey, Bobby? - Yeah?
吉因·麦克拉里打电话找你 是关于工作的
Gene McClary's on the phone, something about a job.
嗯 再打18英尺深 我马上会来
Uh. Get some more 18 inch sinkers, I'll be right back.
你还在等什么？
What are you waiting for?
你周日也工作吗？
You working Sundays now?
我给迪尔德莉打电话 她说你每周末都来这儿
Talked to Dierdre, she says you're down here every weekend.
- 杰克这次的活儿亏损了吗？ - 一点儿
- Losing money on this job, Jack?-a bit.
是因为我吗？
'Cause of me?
有时赚钱 有时亏损
Sometimes I'm up, sometimes I'm down.
这很正常
It all comes out in the end.
今天接了一个电话 是以前的老板打来的
Got a call from a guy today. Used to work for him.
- 打算给我一份工作 - 是吗？很体面的工资？
- Offered me a job. - Yeah? Decent pay?
- 80 - 800000吗？
- Eighty. - Thousand?
是的
Yeah.
是我过去赚的一半
It's half what I used to make.
这操蛋的世界
World's a fucked up place.
事实上 我在想...
Actually, I was thinking about...
...继续跟着你干 杰克
...staying on with you, Jack.
我的那种工作 总是提心吊胆
My old job, I was scared all the time.
季度成本报告
The quarterly cost reports,
新人进来失去了一个客户
young guys coming up, losing an account,
或者是谁比我干的好
who was getting ahead of me.
鲍勃 我能和你实话实说吗？
Can I be honest with you, Bobby?
- 当然 - 你应该接受那份工作
- Yeah. - You should take that job.
你是一个相当烂的木匠
You're a shitty carpenter.
天啊
Christ.
这些该死的东西怎么这么沉
Can't make these damn things any lighter?
我呃...我今天是不会给你工钱的
I, uh... I can't pay you for today.
我想我们现在应该开工了 对吧？
Guess we better get started then, huh?
我会成功 为什么？
I will win, why?
为什么？因为我有信心
Why? Because I have faith,
勇气和热情
courage, enthusiasm.
我会成功！为什么？
I will win! Why?
因为我有信心 勇气和热情
Because I have faith, courage, enthusiasm.
我会成功！为什么？
I will win! Why?
因为我有信心 勇气和热情
Because I have faith, courage, enthusiasm.
能买一个铅笔刀吗？很怪的那种？
Could we get a pencil sharpener?
- 当然 - 很怪的那种？
- Sure. - The kind with a crank?
- 哦 就是老式的那种？ - 对 对
- Oh, the old fashioned kind. - Yeah, yeah.
麦克拉里航运公司？
McClary Maritime Associates?
是的虽然目前还没有什么合伙人
Yeah, we don't have any associates yet,
但是管他呢 听起来舒服
but what the hell, it sounds good.
你那个打印机有年头了
The printer's from the dark ages.
我明天会去史泰博 买个新的
I'll stop by Staples tomorrow, get a new one.
好的
OK.
- 很漂亮的办公室 - 还好
- Nice office. - It's not much.
如果我第一年就能赚回来成本 我会很高兴的
If I make the overhead the first year, I'll be happy.
前几天兰去了本·威尔森那里
Ran into Ben Wilson the other day.
她说你打算投资什么
He said you were going out to possible investors.
是的我打算买下格罗斯特
Yeah, I'm gonna make a bid for Gloucester.
- 那个造船厂？ - 是的
- The shipyard? - Yeah.
安奈特公司不想要
Allied doesn't want it.
我已经找到了很有能力的人
I've already got the skilled labor,
正在和工会谈判
I'll just renegotiate with the unions.
先给的低点看看会不会涨
Start slow, see if it'll grow.
我认为那是个有价值的地方
I think there's a business there.
周二 一起吃个午饭怎么样？
Any time for lunch, Tuesday?
不了
No.
我过去坐在会议室里讨论怎样毁掉别人的生活
I sat in rooms and talked about how to destroy people's lives.
我以为我可以从内部做很多事
I thought I could do more from the inside.
该保留哪里的工作
Save a few jobs here and there.
如果我不做的话 别人也会做
If I didn't do it, somebody else would.
记住我把我当作一个潜在的合伙人
Keep me in mind for a possible associate.
我想我可能也需要另找一份工作
I think I may be looking for a job.
- 替我跟吉因问个好 - 我看起来怎么样？
- Say hello to Gene for me. - How do I look?
肯定会应聘成功
Highly employable.
去吧 不要迟到
Go on, you don't want to be late.
- 过来 - 我爱你
- Come here. - I love you.
我也爱你
I love you.
好了 希望你们有毅力整天在这里
All right. Hope you had your fill
盯着各种各样价格
of sitting around the house all day watching Price is Right.
该工作了 不要抱怨这里的豪华条件
Time to get working now. Don't complain about the luxury accommodations here.
吉因几乎花掉了他运通卡里的所有钱
Gene's basically kickstarting this thing on his AMEX card.
如果你想打动客户就要厚着脸皮上
If you want to impress a client, take them to the Upper Crust.
先分配任务 黛安妮？
Buy them a slice. Diane?
如果我们要保持竞争力的话
I'm gonna need you to do some seller financing
我需要你做一些关于卖方融资和长期租赁的市场调查
and long term lease backs, if we want to stay competitive.
调查一下我们老客户的金融状况
So, run financials on our old customers,
供应商 资本开支运算以及未来的需求
vendors, capital expenditure budgets, future needs.
- 我明白了 - 好的
- You got it. - OK.
科纳尔 我需要那些工会联盟的人回来
Conal. We need our union guys back.
- 要多少？ - 我不知道 也许100个？
- How many? - I don't know, a hundred?
自己看着办 先从当地开始找看看谁愿意来
Something like that. Start with the local, see who's available.
- 我敢打赌每个人都愿意来 - 技工 机械师
- I'm betting everyone. - Mechanics, machinists,
装配师 焊工工程师
fabricators, welders, engineers.
先从以前的同事中找
Start with the crew chiefs.
我们要像之前找工作一样努力工作
We work as hard in here every day as we did
我们就会慢慢好起来的
trying to get a job, we're gonna be all right.
再糟糕还能怎么样？解雇我们？
What's the worst thing they could do? Fire us?
法院正在调查英国巴克利斯银行
Court is exploring whether or not the British bank Barklys
是否利用了雷曼兄弟的破产
took advantage of the collapse of Lehman Brothers.
该银行在雷曼破产后第二天
The UK bank made billions when it bought the
即以不到二十亿收购其经纪业务
US brokerage business days after the company failed,
之后盈利数十亿...
paying less than 2 billion...
罗里德·萨乐奇说今年
Rolid Sallerge says that this
华尔街高管得到一百八十亿的分红
latest round of 18 billion in bonuses
会激起美国民众的愤怒
might be offensive to many Americans...
报道还说 有必要...
and it went on to say, it is necessary if they were...
这些肮脏的收入中
at least $100 Billion of these obscene earnings
至少有一千亿应被没收 返还纳税人
should be confiscated to pay back all the taxpayers
而不是用于将这些混蛋保释出来...
than bailed these bastards out...
我已经失业两年了
I've been out of work 2 years.
我姐姐和她的孩子住在车里
My sister and her kids are living in their car.
学校破产了 医疗体系也很失败...
We got broken schools and a failing health care system...
问题是
The question here is,
他们是否违法了
whether did they do anything illegal?
而不是擅自挪用
not whether it was unethical
客户的钱而不揭发
to take investors money without disclosing the firm
公司在做看空投资
was betting against the investment
的这种行为是否道德
they were selling to its own customers...
现在他们却在抱怨年底分红
And now they're whining their bonuses are
只有二百万而非三百万
only 2 million bucks this year, instead of 3...
...今早报道称
... released a report this morning
联邦抵押贷款项目没能
saying the federal mortgage programs
有效地帮助家庭摆脱房产被没收的命运
aren't doing enough to help more families out of foreclosure.
实业跟踪公司报道称超过九十万...
Realty Track reports over 900,000...
就是电视广告的翻版
Yet, a paraphrase of the old TV commercial,
这些私募基金的家伙
these private equity guys,
他们用过时的方法赚钱
they make money the old fashioned way...
他们剽窃
they steal it.